ERIC BELTRAN | PRODUCT MANAGER

eric@ericbeltran.com www.ericbeltran.com 703-966-5406

An experienced product manager in building both web and mobile products to improve users lives in the real world. Demonstrated strong ability to influence key stakeholders to move the needed metrics for growth. Employs continuous self-improvement through non-stop reading, learning, teaching, and implementing new concepts and practices.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

CONT	ACTUALLY,	WASHINGTON, DC	FEB 2017 -	PRESENT
------	-----------	----------------	------------	---------------------------

SENIOR PRODUCT MANAGER | CONTACTUALLY WEB APP

Senior Product Manager, reporting to VP of Product, of a squad consisting of five in-house full-stack engineers, one in-house UX designer, and one remote QA specialist. Followed two-week agile sprint process to plan, develop, and measure a series of experiments to improve new user onboarding and overall contact management functionality.

- Led optimization split test of our onboarding experience for new users including several rounds of iteration and tests resulted in a final user flow that saw a 13% increase in median WoW retention rates (over weeks 2-4); a 91% increase in expansion ARR; and a 32% increase in the gross count of teams (accounts) that expanded (added seats)
- Led experiment of UX redesign to increase database organization events across all users which resulted in a 9% increase for user first-day events and a 27% increase for user first-week events
- Increased median new user first-week session count by 24% through updated onboarding drip email campaign and inapp CTAs geared towards account setup
- Managed design, build, and release of an updated Android mobile app (React Native) which increased WAU (Android
 users) counts by 89% over seven-month period
- Increased overall ADAU and AWAU counts by 26% and 15% respectively over a twelve-month period
- Increased our four-step activation funnel conversion by 59% (third step) and 124% (fourth step) over a twelve-month period
- Increased the percentage of unique users who send a message (in-app) on their first day (a key metric) by 168% over a five-month period

K12	INSIGHT	, HERNDON	, VA	2013 -	- 201	7
-----	---------	-----------	------	--------	-------	---

PRODUCT MANAGER | LET'S TALK! WEB APP

- Increased daily active users by 200% through launch of weekly usage digest emails
- Introduced and implemented new specification template for all new features improved teams conceptual
 understanding of the solution and reinforced buy-in at all levels
- Managed eight major releases over a two-year period
- Decreased design timeline by 25% through implementation of web style guide
- Increased new user understanding by 50% through launch of automated onboarding feature
- Introduced new metric measurements and monitoring for leadership team to help drive stronger culture of data-driven decision-making

MOBILE PRODUCT MANAGER | LET'S TALK! MOBILE APP

- Conceptualized and launched new app targeted towards parents and students
- Designed the initial mockups and UI, which cut design timeline by 50%
- Saw over 5,000 downloads within twelve-month period
- · Conducted and led number of in-person and virtual user research interviews to gather data points of usage
- Worked with UX and Design to craft new experiences where current users were experiencing friction

Led redesign of app complete with full UI lift and user-centered design approach (launch anticipated Q1 2017)

PRODUCT MANAGER | LEARNING CENTER

- Conceptualized and launched the first version of the Learning Center
- Developed content authoring workflow to control the quality of content and the tone
- Migrated 100+ articles and videos from existing knowledge base to Learning Center

K12, INC., HERNDON, VA 2010 – 2013

PROJECT MANAGER

- Credited with great leadership during all phases of e-learning courseware development
- Thorough attention to detail and strong technical background allowed me to consistently deliver projects to required scope, quality, timescale, and budget in a demanding and fast-paced work environment
- Successfully led remote team of support technicians to deliver solutions to large volume of support related issues across key lines of business
- Worked directly with key clients to resolve issues, alleviate concerns, and nurtured relationships back to health, avoiding
 possible non-renewals
- Routinely demonstrated a strong ability to operate comfortably against short deadlines, maintained sense of urgency during crunch times, and sustained professionalism within demanding and stressful situations

KC DISTANCE LEARNING, PORTLAND, OR 2007 – 2010

SENIOR DEVELOPER

- Initiated construction of an internal standards repository for web development team, which housed a knowledge center consisting of best practices and standards
- Knowledge center adoption eventually decreased instances of non-compliant development issues resulting in increased value and marketability of products.
- Designed, developed, and delivered SCORM friendly online training course for internal training program. Efforts included preparing course materials, developing assessments, and managing participant data

DEVELOPER

- Integral team member of Curriculum Delivery team, responsible for development of over 200 SCORM friendly K-12 online and hybrid courses
- · Owned variety of projects and learned to operate in fast paced environment without sacrificing attention to detail

EDUCATION

Product Management Bootcamp

MINOT STATE UNIVERSITY 2016

Master of Science, Management of Information Systems Severson Entrepreneurship Academy

Bachelor of Arts, Multimedia Design

Bachelor of Arts, International Studies: Human Rights and Conflict Resolution